+91-8754802671

CAREER OBJECTIVE:

Seeking a Dot Net Professional positions in a progressive challenging environment where my technical experience would add value. Work in innovative projects to enhance myself as a software developer and contribute for the growth of organization.

EXPERIENCE SNAPCHAT:

- Having 3+ Years of experience in .NET Technologies.
- Excellent knowledge in Object Oriented Programming Concepts.
- Proficient at developing .NET Framework web applications.
- Hands-on experience in WCF and Web Services.
- Hands-on experience in database technologies like Microsoft SQL Server.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Company	Designation	Duration
Cognizant Technology	Associate	18 Nov 2017 –till date
Solutions		

TECHNICAL SKILLSET:

Operating System	Windows	
Languages	C#	
Database	MS SQL Server	
Web Technologies	ASP.Net, ADO.Net, .NET Core,LINQ, Web	
	Services, WCF, Web API,MVC, Entity	
	Framework, AJAX, Bootstrap, React js	
Web / Application Server	Internet Information Services (IIS)	
Scripting Languages	Java Script, JQuery	
Tools	HP ALM, JIRA, Fortify Audit Tool	
Version Control System	GIT	
Domains	Telecommunication and Media	

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION:

COURSE	INSTITUTION	YEAR OF PASSING	MARKS IN % or CGPA
B.E Computer Science and Engineering	Velammal Engineering College	2017	8.64 CGPA
Higher Secondary	St. Joseph's Girls' Higher Secondary School	2013	93 %
SSLC	St. Joseph's Girls' Higher Secondary School	2011	95.6%

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY:

Project 3: My Info (Customer Care Employee's Performance Management System)		
Client	Verizon Telecommunications Feb 2020 – till date	
Domain	Telecom	
Software and Tools	ASP.NET, MVC, .NET CORE, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, WEB	
	API, Web Services, SQL, Entity Framework, ADO.NET, Fortify	
	Audit Tool	
Role	Software Developer	
Responsibilities	Analyzing the Requirement	
	 Developing the application 	
	Unit test case preparation	
	 Code build and Deployment in Jenkins 	
Project Overview	My Info PM tool is having various browser based application	
	exposed to Verizon's customer care service employees to analyze	
	and record the customer care employee's performance by their	
	supervisor, and view their own performance. This system provides	
	various services like customer care employee's performance	
	management, customer care calls management, employee's rating	
	management, employee's skill up management.	

Project 2: CSI (Custome	er Service Interface) Nov 2017 -Jan 2020	
Client	Ooredoo , Oman	
Onsite Experience	Worked at Muscat for couple of month (Aug 19 – Sep 19 and Dec	
	19-Jan 20) and performed Integration testing.	
Domain	Telecom	
Software and Tools	ASP.Net, C#, User Controls, WCF, Java Script, JQuery, CSS, AJAX,	
	ASMX Web Services, Entity Framework, Telerik Controls	
Role	Software Developer	
Responsibilities	Preparing all the design artifacts	
	 Coding ,Unit Testing and Integration testing 	
	Unit test case preparation	

	Code build and Deployment in IIS	
Project Overview	CSI is a browser-based user interface portal exposed as SOA model with role-based access and features for the customer service	
	agents of Ooredoo. It provisions various services such as Customer	
	Management, Channel and Payment Gateway Services, Product	
	Offering service, Order Management, Credit Score Working	
	management, Sale and Post Sale services. It offers services to	
	Residential and Corporate Customers for their Mobile and Fixed	
	line connections.	

Project 1: Text based vio	leo indexing (UG Project)	Dec 2016 – Apr 2017
Software and Tools	Java, JSP, HTML, CSS, SQL Server	
Role	Developer	
Responsibilities	 Preparing all the design artifacts 	
	 Coding ,Unit Testing 	
Project Overview	Developed a Tool which indexes the vid	leo dynamically. It allows
	user to search relevant words and plays from the specific topic they	
	want. We processed the subtitle of each	video file to locate the
	exact occurrences of the word.	

APPRECIATIONS:

- Awarded 'PAT on the back' for the month of October 2018 from Cognizant Communication and media domain.
- Awarded 'Hats Off' certification for the quarters Q4- 2018 and Q1-2019 from Cognizant Communication and media domain..

PERSONAL EXPERIENCE:

Date Of Birth : 31/07/1996

Father's Name : R.Muthu

Sex : Female

Nationality : Indian

Marital Status : Single

Permanent Address : 24, South Madappa Lane, Kumbakonam, 612001.

DECLARATION:

I hereby declare that the above written particulars are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place: Chennai SASIREKHA MUTHU